[PASSIONATE MOANS]
ABBY:
Max, stop. We
can't. She'll find us.
MAX:
No she won't.
Oh, God.
ALICE:
Max?
We can't!
So what if she finds us?
You don't mean that.
What if I do?
ALICE:
Max? Max, Where are you?
Oh there you are, you two! Good
Lord! Ten years and you are
still at it? Come on! Your
guests are
wondering where you are.
[ACOUSTIC GUITAR]
¶I'm alright
I'm okay¶
¶I will make it either way¶
¶After all the
things you put me through¶
¶I still love you¶
[CROWD CLAPPING]
ARTHUR:
I'm so nervous. I'm not
used to people actually
listening to me when I sing.
Arthur! I
missed your last two songs!
You snooze you lose. I
uh, played your favorite.
No you didn't. "Luna's Crush" is
my favorite, and you know it!
So you did hear me!
In the background, but I
prefer to be right here where I
can just gaze at
you and just be like in awe.
LORNA:
Don't layer it on so thick, Abs.
What are you
doing over here all by yourself?
Married a decade. Who does that?
Lots of people.
Not in this city.
And not happily.
BARRY:
Lorna, I could make you happy
if you'd give me a chance.
For one night maybe.
For one more
night you mean?
You wish.
Henry, she doesn't
remember this but one
traumatically romantic evening.
Lorna walked me under a
blanket of glittering stars on
the aptly named 'Sandy Beach' in
Honolulu, Oahu. That's Hawaii.
LORNA:
Oh, Is that where Honolulu is?
I pointed out
the constellations-
Yeah right.
I carried her
flip flops for her.
That never happened!
MAX:
The four of us did
go to Oahu two years ago.
Max and I did go to bed earlier
than you two.
I'm sure it wasn't to sleep!
[BLUBBERING]
Hey!
If you all think for one second
that I seriously hooked up with
this schmo-
Hey, hey, hey! This schmo's got
a really big reason
for you to hook up with him.
GROUP:
Oh no, no, no, no, no!
ALICE:
You better
calm down and be careful
because I might just leave
my husband for you!
HENRY:
I dare
you, Barry. She's a wildcat.
Oh God, you
say the nicest things!
And them.
See, that's
what I'm talking about, Henry!
Screw ten years! I'm going for
forty-three! And
I'm gonna start right now.
Lorna, you tight ass snob.
Alright Barry. Pull it back.
What? I'm
proposing! God help
if I know why? Look at that
judgment just staring back at me
like you're better than me. Huh?
Like you're better
than everybody else!
HENRY:
Get up, Barry.
JENNIFER:
Abby, we're gotta get going.
No!
Open your gift.
No no no no no,
is it because of...
TOM:
No, are you kidding?
It ain't a party without
Barry acting like a jackass.
Jackass? What
did you call me, Tom?
You're going to wear that
vest, and call me a jackass?
C'mon, Barry.
Let's get you some coffee.
No no, I'm good. Yeah. I'm fine.
Sorry, Barry.
Don't fucking apologize to him.
Okay, okay.
Arthur, another song?
Guys. Just
stay a little longer?
It's really early still.
Fine. We'll stick around.
For you guys.
Lorna and Barry really...
No!
No no. No way. It's his favorite
pastime to make her angry.
Oh okay good. I mean,
I've been thinking of
asking her out, but I
gotta admit, she scares me.
Maybe wait until she doesn't.
Well, if
you could put in a word for me.
[HUMMING WEDDING MARCH]
Shut up.
[PARTY SOUNDS IN BACKGROUND]
[ACOUSTIC STRUMMING]
Oh, what've you got here?
Seghesio 2012.
Oh! Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you!
Where's Henry?
Not doing the
dishes, I can tell you that.
I miss you.
Tom wants to bet me the
Falcons will win this weekend.
What? That's crazy. Take it.
Oh, I did.
You should get in on this.
[CLATTER WITH GASPS]
I am so sorry Abs.
It's totally fine.
It was our mother's.
Shit. I'm so sorry.
It's just "a thing".
Well done, Grace.
Will you give me
a fucking break for once in
your fucking life?
I think I'm about done with
this. C'mon Barry, let's go.
I'll make sure
you get home okay.
I'm fine. I
promise I won't touch anything.
Barry, I love you.
But when you get like this...
If she weren't such a-
If you weren't so wasted, it
wouldn't matter what Lorna did.
Fine. If I gotta go,
I'ma take a beer with me.
Let's go to the cabin tomorrow.
I wanna stay here
for the weekend.
Just do nothing. Just rest.
You always complain
there's nothing to do up there.
I do not complain! Alright,
I complain a little bit. But
that's because there's nothing
to do at the cabin. There's too
much nothing. You know I think
it's boring as hell up there.
I'll keep you busy.
This family!
We know too much! Too much!
I'm sorry.
Alright.
Luna's crush!
[CROWD CHEERING]
Okay. Okay.
¶You are the ocean
you shine heavenly¶
¶The sky is your halo,
you're capturing me¶
¶Now I am like rain¶
¶I'm falling for you¶
¶Luna's
Crush has lost its words¶
[DOOR KNOCKING]
¶Drowning in a sea of nerves¶
¶Don't know what to say for the¶
[DOOR KNOCKING]
¶last time¶
[SOFT PIANO]
[NO CRYING HEARD,
JUST THE PIANO NOTES]
[SOFT PIANO CONTINUES]
[MUSIC FADES]
What kind
of balls does this
take? I mean, wow.
Arthur, he was my best friend.
Yeah, A lot of
good that did him!
You're really
going to say that now, Barry?
Okay, cut it out!
We're all hurting here.
Yeah, we wouldn't be if this
guy could hold a drink down.
Fuck you!
Max is gone,
and you can't undo it.
He's not worth it Arthur.
Oh my God.
Arthur, take a walk with me.
Yeah, why don't you guys take
a walk and get some fresh air?
Babe?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry, Mrs. O'Connell.
[SOMBER PIANO CONTINUES]
[WHIMPERS]
How you doin' kid?
Yeah, me too.
Did I ever tell
you this story? When Max met
you, he woke me up at three
o'clock in the morning. Three
AM! Damn kid.
You guys had
met at a bar, hence the late
hour, and he said
he'd kept you talking all night
by stealing your keys out of
your purse,
holding them in the air
until you agreed to stay.
But
you know that part, don't you?
Well, he woke me up, whispering
so his mother didn't hear. I
think he was afraid she might
put the story in
one of her novels.
He said, "Dad, I met
her. I found the girl."
I tried
to shut him up so I could get
back to sleep, but he said,
"No, Dad! She's my wife, Dad
I found my wife."
I told him, "I thought
you said all girls were crazy."
You know what he said? "Well,
I'm gonna make this one crazy
about me."
I know that you know
this, Abby girl, but the love
you feel, and the loss,
my boy feels it, too. I
know he's watching us,
and he feels
just as badly as we do.
This was a
mistake. God made a mistake.
Henry, I...
What'd you two talk
about on the way home?
Uh. We
spoke about women.
I told him they're all crazy.
He was amused.
He said...
What?
He said, 'That's
what makes them so interesting.'
I told him that...
You did?
Yeah when he was, God I
don't remember. Fifteen?
Seventeen? He was dating
that blonde. What was her name?
Parker.
That's right.
Parker. Such a nut.
I told him
to enjoy. Just don't marry her.
Marry someone
who's got some balance.
I haven't gone to her
yet. I don't think I can.
Give her time.
Are you going to stay with her?
As long as
she'll let me. She took
care of me
when our parents died.
Call
us if you need us to come back.
We can stay in the guest room.
You'd have to kick
me out then. Ain't gonna
happen. Do you
guys need anything?
Just one thing.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Abs? I need to hear your voice.
I don't know what to do.
Nothing.
That's what you do. Nothing.
Just rest and...time. They say
that thing about time. I
won't bore you with the adage.
Time doesn't know me very well.
I will never get over this.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
BARRY:
My name is Barry,
and I'm an alcoholic.
GROUP:
Hi Barry.
BARRY:
Many of you
know what happened.
I'm struggling with a lot of
guilt, I feel like this is
how my life is gonna play out.
I don't want a drink.
I know that for sure. The sight
of booze doesn't make me
thirsty, it makes
me want to cry.
[CITY SOUNDS]
[CELL PHONE CHIME]
BARRY:
I just wanna go
back. Instead I have to live
with this forever.
[NATURE SOUNDS]
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC]
[MELANCHOLIC ORCHESTRA]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hey you.
Where are you?
I decided to
stay home. Watch TV.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
ABBY:
None of the stuff
I'm doing is working, Jen. I
just, I don't fit here.
ABBY:
Here.
In this city. In that job.
From the woman who was destined
to be king
of the company one day?
ABBY:
Not queen?
JENNIFER:
No. King.
ABBY:
What they don't tell
you when someone you love dies
is you realize how short life
really is. I was hustling all
the time, for what? All that
stuff we were buying,
who cares about any of it?
JENNIFER:
You're grieving.
But you are worrying us.
Abby.
You're not keeping any of this?
Isn't that a little extreme?
LORNA:
You hate the country!
I'm not coming to visit you.
ABBY:
I don't want you to.
We have
dishes and furniture and
everything we
need at the cabin, so...
ALICE:
We?
LORNA:
I'm going to say it again.
ABBY:
Please don't.
LORNA:
This is not your fault.
ABBY:
You said it.
LORNA:
And here it comes again. What
happened to
Max is not your fault.
ABBY:
I know that.
LORNA
Do you?
ALICE:
What are you
going to do for money?
ABBY:
Max made us take out life
insurance policies right after
we got married.
ALICE:
I told him to do that. How much?
ABBY:
Enough to live off of
if I continue to invest it
properly.
At least at the
cabin, I don't
have as many memories.
ALICE:
That was Max's favorite
place. He's everywhere there.
ABBY:
I know.
ALICE:
Oh, I see.
[SAD ORCHESTRAL STRINGS]
[MELANCHOLIC
ORCHESTRA CONTINUES]
[CLOCK TICKING
UNDERNEATH MUSIC]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
[WHIMPERING]
[MUSIC FADES]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
WANDA:
Are you
visiting family?
Sorry?
WANDA:
You don't look like you're from
around here and I know everyone.
No. I just moved in.
Are you a writer? We
get a lot of writers up here.
I'm not a writer.
What do you do then?
Are you a
gardener? We have this great
volunteer gardening
group that tends to all the
local businesses that can't
afford big time landscaping
companies. Keeps the town
looking pretty, you know?
Blooming all year 'round.
Does everyone
know everybody here?
The
town as a whole is a
tight-knit
group, a lot of loyalty.
That's great. Have a nice day.
You too!
Jack! Well, aren't
you a sight for sore eyes.
Wanda, where
have you been all my life?
Stop it!
[ETHEREAL MUSIC]
[SOMBER, DAUNTING]
Max?
Is that you?
I can smell you.
[THE MUSIC PUNCTUATES
HER SORROW]
Max?
Come back to me.
[NIGHT SOUNDS MIX
WITH THE MUSIC]
You don't know
how good it was just to breathe
you in just one more time.
I'm
losing it. I don't know what
I'm doing.
I'm really just...
Hi.
Oh my God.
You can see me?
Is it really you?
It's really me.
Oh my God.
Oh my-
[EXCLAIMS]
Yeah, that's probably not a
good idea. I can't catch you
anymore.
You're shivering.
Let's get you inside.
It's not from the cold.
It's not just from
seeing a ghost either. I know
what you've been eating. We have
to get you inside or you'll get
sick. It's okay.
I'm going with you.
Am I dreaming?
You're not dreaming.
Have you been
here this whole time?
No, I came here with you.
You've been
with me this whole time?
Yes. Sometimes
I've gone to my parent's.
It killed me to see them crying.
Abs, I can't
believe you can see me.
Why now?
How come now?
I don't know.
Are you stuck here?
MAX:
I don't know.
ABBY:
Are they going to take
you away from me again?
They? I don't know
about any "they," Abby.
I miss you so much.
It's been hell without you.
I never thought I
was going to see you again.
I'm here. I'm right here.
MAX:
But I can never
get closer than that.
No, it wasn't hard to quit.
That's surprising.
I bet.
You saw me, right? I lost the
passion for it when you...
But you loved your job.
I loved the status.
You loved the money, too.
We should have
gone on more vacations.
Now she says that.
Come on.
That's not fair. Or kind.
I was kidding.
We should've
spent more time together.
I have all the
time in the world now.
Where do you want to go?
I heard that tone in
your voice. You're judging me.
How can I judge? I would've
probably done the same thing
you've done.
No, you wouldn't have. You
would've been like your mother,
strong, helping everybody get
over me.
I'm not strong like you.
Yes, you are.
You've just forgotten.
Get some sleep, baby.
No! You'll be gone again.
Remember when I
threatened to throw you into the
pool at Tom and Jennifer's?
I said "you wouldn't dare".
And I said, "I promised I
would."
And then you
did. And you said...
I always keep my promises.
I promise you, I will
be here when you wake up.
How do you know? Maybe they'll
take you away from me in the
middle of the night.
They?
I don't think they're
going to do that.
I promise.
Because I
think I'm supposed to help you.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Max!
Hey.
Hey. Have I lost my nut?
Did you only have one?
Probably not the right term.
I like it.
I don't know what to do.
How about cleaning up a little?
No! No.
Come on,
I'll keep you company.
We'll dance it out.
[MARVIN GAYE'S HEARD IT THROUGH
THE GRAPEVINE FADES IN]
¶Oh. I bet you're
wonderin' how I knew¶
¶'Bout your plans
to make me blue¶
¶With some other
guy you knew before¶
¶Between the two of us guys¶
¶You know I loved you more¶
¶It took me by
surprise I must say¶
¶When I found out yesterday¶
¶Don'tcha know that I
heard it through the grapevine¶
¶Not much longer
would you be mine¶
¶Oh, I heard it
through the grapevine¶
¶Oh, I'm just
about to lose my mind¶
¶Honey, honey, yeah¶
¶I heard it
through the grapevine¶
¶Not much longer
would you be mine baby, ohh¶
¶I know a man
ain't supposed to cry¶
¶But these
tears I can't hold inside¶
¶Losin' you would
end my life you see¶
¶Cause you mean that much to me¶
¶You could have
told me yourself¶
¶That you loved someone else¶
¶Instead I heard it
through the grapevine¶
¶Not much longer
would you be mine¶
¶Oh, I heard it
through the grapevine¶
¶And I'm just
about to lose my mind¶
¶Honey, honey, yeah¶
¶I heard it
through the grapevine¶
¶Not much longer would
you be mine, baby, ooh¶
[SOFT RAIN]
Get some veggies.
Alright! You're
beginning to annoy me.
Baby broccoli.
Ooh, I can sauté it.
There ya go.
Just so you know, I will
be getting ice cream.
You can't stop me.
Stop you? I want some!
Baby broccoli.
You get this
from your mother.
Mother knows best.
You look happy
today. Got a hot date?
Me? No. It's
just me and me tonight.
You're going
to eat both of these?
Tell her.
Hush. Hush
now, you'll make me blush,
Wanda. No, it's just me.
I'll make
the second one tomorrow I guess.
Your skin looks rosier.
Thanks.
You getting good sleep?
Yeah.
Here let me get that. Oh,
oh, I'll get the front door!
Have a nice day.
You too, honey.
Look at this place. The
best thing I ever did, besides
marrying you,
was buying these acres.
It's very beautiful.
You always hated coming here.
Now look at you, ordering
delivery and hanging out with me
for almost a month.
I did not hate it.
That's too strong a word.
Hm.
Okay, it wasn't my favorite
thing to do, but the drive!
It's two hours!
Of me
white-knuckling it while you
drive the speed of
light! Not comfortable.
I miss coffee.
Oh that's
good. That's real good.
That's it. Live it up.
Yes, oh, hmm...
Have you seen a light?
Not yet. Think
that means I'm going to hell?
I don't believe in hell. I think
hell is living on Earth without
you. And I don't recommend it.
But you believe in lights.
A lot of
people have seen them.
So, what do
you want to do today?
You want to come
with me to a bookstore?
Oh shit.
Now you have to come!
I don't have to do
anything. I'm not tethered to
you, woman. I can sit here and
stare at the
pretty trees if I wanted.
Bookstore it is.
Yay!
But you're driving!
MAX:
You ever think
about getting a dog?
Why
would I want a dog?
To keep you company.
I have company. I have you.
Yeah but I
can't lick your face. Sleep in
your lap.
Shed all over your couch.
Oh, you're making it
more appetizing by the second.
Oh, I forgot my
wedding ring by the sink.
You wanna wear mine?
Oh, Look! An old
copy of Little Women!
Yay.
I'm going to
read it to you, cover to cover.
Don't you dare.
CUSTOMER:
Excuse me?
Oh, I wasn't talking to you.
She was talking to me! Hey! You
got a problem. You
want to take this outside?
Oh my God.
Seriously, sir. I need to know.
What is the appeal of books when
you can just watch the movie?
Because the
film is never as good as the
book which you would know if you
ever read a book.
What? I read all
the time. That's why I'm here.
I'm sorry. I
wasn't talking to you. I was
having one of those old
arguments in my head. Don't you
ever play out those
old arguments from your...
JACK:
I do that. All the time.
Oh, hi.
Hi. Sorry, I just...I just
thought I should
come to your defense
instead of leaving you hanging
out there in the cold. That's
Mike. He's like that with
everyone.
I wouldn't take offense.
I'm Jack.
I heard you're new in town!
"Jo vanished without a word.
Rushing upstairs, she startled
the invalids by exclaiming
tragically as she burst into the
room, 'Oh, do somebody go down
quick; John Brooke is acting
dreadfully, and Meg likes it!"
You're enjoying it, stop
it. Do you want me to stop?
No.
I'll stop.
No don't stop.
No it's done.
Come on. One more chapter.
Now I have to
find the spot again.
Okay.
"He longed to
lay Amy's head down on his
shoulder and tell her to have
a good cry, but he did not dare.
So he took her hand instead and
gave it a sympathetic squeeze
that was better than words.
Like
a homesick child whose heart was
full, that Laurie
forgot his bashfulness."
[STRINGS SWELL
AND DIALOGUE FADES]
Abs?
Hmm?
I think I see the light.
Yeah.
[MELANCHOLY, YET
SLIGHTLY UPLIFTING PIANO]
ABBY:
Everyone keeps asking me that.
You could open a restaurant.
What do I know
about restaurants?
You could learn.
If I wanted to,
I would. But I don't.
You could
work out of your home,
helping people
grow their businesses.
Use the
marketing skills you have.
No way. I've
left that behind me.
You saw
me at the office, right?
It was too boring to stay long.
Exactly!
Right. Right.
You know uh,
that check-stand lady?
Wanda?
Yes, Wanda. She
said something about gardening.
That didn't sound terrible.
We never had a
plant we didn't kill.
We weren't home
enough to take care of them.
What a waste of time.
We should have had kids.
We always agreed there was
enough people on the planet.
And we wanted
to enjoy our lives. But did we?
Yes. We did. We do.
But now...
No no! No. We wouldn't have
spent... We wouldn't have worked
less if we'd had kids. We
would've just
gotten a nanny. And then they
would've gone to a
therapist and
said we didn't love them.
But then you'd have someone
to love now that I'm gone.
Okay. A: That's a terrible
reason to have a child. And A.5:
What children stay near their
parents when they become adults
anyway? And then B: I have you
now. So why are we even talking
about this? Especially when
we can't do anything about it.
Now granted I am
no longer among the living so
how can I
split hairs but I don't
think there's
any such thing as an A.5.
I made it up.
You made it up.
Of course you did.
I get to
make things up if I want to.
[SCREAMS]
Abby! Hold
on! Help! Someone! Help!
What if I just let go?
Abby, don't!
I could be with you.
No!
It would be so easy.
No, Abby don't
do it! Abby! Don't.
I should have done it.
That's not your
decision to make.
What's
that supposed to mean?
I don't know.
It just felt wrong. It
felt...wrong.
Then whose decision is it?
LORNA:
What happened to you?
ABBY:
I almost fell off a cliff.
LORNA:
What? You okay?
ABBY:
No. Yeah. I don't know.
What's in the bag?
Oh, some wine,
bread, cheese. Sandwich fixings.
Good stuff like that. What do
you mean you fell off a cliff?
I was hiking
and I slipped.
You're not
supposed to hike alone, Abs.
What are you looking at?
Nothing, I was
just making sure the place was
tidy for you.
Looks great. I was
expecting a disaster.
She knows you.
Funny. So what's
been going on in the world?
Same ol' same ol'.
Lorna, what's with the face?
I've been
seeing someone.
You have? The last
boyfriend you had was Sean.
Eck. Don't
remind me. You hungry?
I'm starving.
But let me do it. No no.
You just tell me all about it!
Um. You know him.
Arthur?
Really? I
would terrorize that guy.
Eat him alive. Come on.
You probably would.
Well, then who?
Now let me explain.
No way.
He's been
sober ever since, Abs.
He goes to meetings.
Takes service commitments.
He's not the same guy you knew.
Not Barry.
It turns out he was really in
love with me this whole time.
And I treated him like shit and
he drank more and tried harder
and... it's a
vicious cycle of crap.
Can you believe this shit? He is
the reason my husband is dead!
LORNA:
Abby.
MAX:
Come on.
If he hadn't gotten so
drunk, you wouldn't have been
hit by that car!
Who are you talking to?
Wait wait!
Don't go in there yet!
You have got to be the most
selfish person I have ever met!
Are you kidding me?
I'm so sorry.
I didn't realize you
were going off your rocker.
I'm not crazy.
LORNA:
You were just
talking to thin air! Tell me you
weren't just talking
to your dead husband.
Don't call him that!
Abby! You're acting crazy!
Do I look
fucking crazy to you?
Yes! And pissed.
Yeah, oh I'm
pissed alright because the only
person crazy here is you!
How dare
you bring him here!
You didn't even call
me to warn me. Nothing.
You're the one who said, "Poor
Barry." Think about someone
besides you for a second. Max
was his best friend! He's been
dying over this. Do you have
any idea how much it killed him
that...
There
are a lot of ways we absently
use words connected to death in
common conversation.
I was trying
to forgive him, Lorna.
I know. I should have called and
warned you. Maybe you need to
talk to him. Maybe
it would help you move on.
Tell him not to come inside.
Too late.
I will do
whatever you want, but think
about this. You
both need to heal.
Go get
another bottle of wine from the
store. Then come back.
Okay.
She can't see you.
MAX:
Nope.
What if I'm crazy?
I'm real.
I thought you were sober.
I am. I'm
just being chivalrous.
Come on, Abby.
What?
I'm just acting out of habit.
I wasn't always that bad.
No at first, you were
fun. Later, not so much.
Baby, why won't you look at
me? I'm really
here. You're hurting me.
I never print out photographs
anymore. I didn't
know he printed this one.
I'm so sorry Abby.
Every day I wish I could
go back and take a fucking taxi,
put the drinks down, anything.
I knew it should've been me.
I know
you think that, too. I want
you to know you're right.
It should have been me.
I am so sorry, Abby.
He just had to
go and cry, didn't he?
It wasn't your fault.
It was the fault of
the driver who hit him.
Abby.
How have you been
spending your time up here?
It's pretty lonely.
You make any new friends?
I've been fine.
That didn't answer my question.
I have an idea.
LORNA:
What have
you been doing up here?
Healing.
Yeah, except
for the rage, bottle throwing,
and talking to
yourself, you look better.
Abby, ask Barry about the
fishing trip. Tell him he let
the big one go
because he felt sorry for it.
Abby, How have you
been spending your time?
Do it. Ask. Ask him. I
can prove I'm real! Ask him.
Lorna stop
pressuring her, okay?
I'm sorry, I
was just asking.
It's not that.
Tell them.
I can't!
Can't what?
Why not? Just
ask him about the fucking fish,
Abigail! Let me prove I'm real
to you! Goddammit I can't stand
you not looking at me! Don't
make me go through that again.
And what if
you're not! They're going to
think I'm crazy
and who's gonna have
to deal with that? Me! Not you,
because you're not even real!
That burger's
already burnt, babe.
ABBY:
Oh Shit.
I've
been talking to Max. He's here.
I think. I know you're not
believe me,
but he's right there.
He's here? Do
you think Max is here, honey?
Don't talk to me
like I'm five years old.
Honey, I'm just-
What's up with
the honey's, Lorna?
Just ask Barry about the fish!
Barry, when
you went fishing that day, did
you throw the big fish back
because you felt sorry for it?
Yeah.
Max just told me that.
Yeah, but he could have told you
that when he was still alive.
I'm not saying that
you're nuts, I'm...
No, you're right. He could have.
Tell him to
ask you something only I
would know.
Oh my God, what if I'm crazy?
Tell him!
Abby? Look, it's okay.
We'll get someone to see you.
I'm afraid I'll find out you're
not real! Please don't take this
from me!
Baby,
you've gotta trust me on this.
Tell him to ask you something
only I would know. Please.
I promise you I'm real.
He wants you
to ask me something only he
would know.
Uh, okay. Let me think. Okay?
Come on you
bastard. Make it fucking good.
Have you got one?
No.
Give me a second. Let me think!
Okay I got
it! But close your ears.
No way.
Look, you
know I wasn't always a good guy.
Ask him which married
woman I had sex with on the
bathroom sink in my office.
Helen and Jennifer.
Helen and Jennifer?
Holy shit!
That's two women.
It was a trick question.
I don't know
who Helen is, but Jennifer?
Jennifer of Tom and Jennifer?
They were
going through a rough patch.
Wait, Abby, he could have told
you that when
he was still alive!
I guarantee you
he did not tell me that!
Tell him he said that Jennifer
tasted like strawberries.
He said Jennifer
tasted like strawberries?
And not just strawberries.
I think he actually said
"organic strawberries
lit by an afternoon sun."
Organic strawberries
lit by an afternoon sun.
Holy shit!
He would never fuckin' tell you
that! Because you girls would
never keep
that shit to yourselves!
Organic strawberries-
I didn't mean anything by
that, baby. That was way before
us and I was in love with you.
Well, if she was so damned
delicious, why'd you give it up?
Because I was in love with you.
LORNA:
Watch it.
Baby. It was before
us. And I'm in love with you.
What do I taste like?
You're real.
Max?
He's looking at you, Barry.
Where is he?
He's standing right there.
Max, God, buddy.
I'm so fucking sorry.
I'm so sorry!
Please, please forgive me.
I forgive you, Barry.
He says he forgives you.
I've gotta go.
No.
I'll be back. I
just need a moment.
What'd he say?
He's gone.
You okay?
I gotta go for a walk.
You want me to come?
No. I gotta go alone.
Okay.
He's real.
How
long have you seen him?
I was a mess.
I might have starved to death if
he hadn't shown up.
Why didn't you call me?
But for how long,
Abby? Can you spend the rest of
your life with the
ghost of your husband?
Why not?
Because you need someone to
touch. You're a human being.
You need that! Believe me, I
went without it for a fuck of a
long time. It's not healthy.
No offense, but you
don't know what I need.
I just want you to be happy.
I am happy.
Just stop talking.
I'm gonna go make dinner. We
need more to
eat than wine and cynicism.
I'm sorry you had to sleep on
the couch. I
forget the sofa bed broke.
It's fine. The
couch itself isn't broken.
Is he here?
No.
He was here. I woke up and found
him watching me sleep. So I
guess I'm glad you came. At
least now I
know I'm not bonkers.
Glad I'm good for something.
Barry. You
have to forgive yourself now.
Can you?
Yes.
So what have you
guys been up to?
We went to a bookstore. I read
a book to him. Little Women.
Shut up.
The whole thing.
No, no, no.
Truth. Other
than that we've
just been spending time
together. He's here, you know?
Wild. But...
Don't. I
already heard it from my sister.
No doubt.
She's a ball buster.
Apparently you
don't want your balls.
Oh I do. She loves them.
I'm sorry I went there!
Hey. Morning.
Woo! It's freezing in here!
I'm gonna go chop some firewood.
Oh, thank you!
I was wondering how I was going
to do that now that...
The uh, best
thing about not drinking? I can
swing an ax around
without the hangover. Woohoo!
Balls!
Jeez!
That's
not the best thing, but it's
something! How'd you
sleep out here? Was it terrible?
No, it was
fine. How'd you sleep?
When you were
hiking, was Max there?
Yes, why?
And you fell.
What, do you
think he pushed me?
No.
Give me one good reason to
move on because I sure as hell
can't think of any.
Don't you want to touch
him? Feel his arms around you?
Kiss him?
You're killing me.
I just want you to
be happy. Truly happy.
I am happy, damnit. No, I
can't touch him. But I can see
him. I can hear him. I can laugh
with him. I am so very, very
sick of you trying to
make me feel badly about this.
I'm sorry.
I'm not trying to hurt you.
I'm trying to-
Look, don't take
this the wrong way, I just
really want the place to myself
again. Go worry about me from
home. Because This? This I
don't need. I'm going to take a
shower.
Max?
I don't know if you're here or
not, but if you are, listen up.
Stop being selfish.
You don't know anything.
Fucking bugs.
She's going
to be an old woman living in
this drafty cabin all by herself
holding onto the man she lost in
a freak accident?
It''s not healthy.
If you love her,
you'll do the right thing.
[DOOR BANGS]
BARRY:
Hey, open up!
My arms are full.
Good thing
someone's here to chop wood.
It sure is
cold in here. Can you feel it?
Man, it must have dropped
twenty degrees last night!
Max, if you're here buddy,
I love you, man.
I miss you.
And about
what I was saying. I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
Okay, I'm not.
We'll leave you
two alone now.
So weird.
Babe?
Max?
Babe, I'm going to
the store and get some eggs
and stuff. You wanna come?
Okay it's been
several long days of the cold
shoulder and since you're not
talking to me, you can't argue
with me, either. I don't know
what happened
when they were here,
but if you think you're helping
me by staying away, you're not.
I need you, handsome. Please
come back to me.
[QUIET SOUNDS OF NATURE]
[TRAFFIC SOUNDS]
Hey!
Morning. Sorry I startled you
the other
morning at the bookstore.
You have a little something.
I, uh, what?
You have a
little something on your face.
Oh no, is it bad?
You should be mortified.
Like when the bird pooped on my
head Freshman year mortified?
Was that high
school or college?
That was high school.
Oh, then yes definitely.
Oh dear.
There? There? Yeah. Eh. Well.
Hey check this out. So I had
potted plants over there and I
came back and they're gone! So
I'm thinking people liked 'em
enough to steal 'em or birds
absconded with them to Belize.
Absconded to Belize?
Yep!
Really?
That's my best guess.
Are you a gardener?
Landscaper. So
yeah, you could say that.
There's this moss I saw
growing on the cedars up here
that's like tiny feathers or
something you'd
see swaying in the ocean
And then
I was walking along this rock
that's light grey almost
to the point of being white.
That's conglomerate
quartz. It's beautiful.
Conglomerate quartz.
Have you been
to the waterfall?
Hm, hm.
Perhaps I could take you
sometime. Because you're a moss
enthusiast. There's a moss that
grows on the rocks down at the
bottom, it's so green it's
almost blue. You'd think you're
in Scotland.
Is that where you're from?
Yeah, my
family is from there. So...
Abby?
Well, what a surprise!
Alice! Henry!
What are you
doing all the way up here?
Well, I didn't want to show up
at your place empty-handed and
Henry wanted
to use the bathroom.
You didn't
have to tell everyone that.
No, I meant out here, not
here at the grocery store.
Abby knows you're a human
being, Henry. Everybody has to
go. I don't see what
all the mystery is about.
How I wish you did.
Hi I'm Jack McCaffrey.
McCaffrey? Scottish?
Yeah, it's funny. We were just
talking about
that. My family's from there.
I'm an O'Connell, Henry, Irish
through and through. My mom was
first generation American, but
her accent
never washed off on me.
Pity
that. I'm Alice O'Connell.
Hi Alice, very nice to meet
you. Are these your parents?
Almost.
She's married to our son.
Oh.
That's great.
Was, honey.
Well, she's still married to
him in my mind. Excuse me.
He's not
doing so well, We're
going on a vacation, driving
further up north to get away and
you know...rest. Heal a bit with
some fresh scenery. I thought
it'd be a good idea to pop in
and see how you're doing, but
the second I mentioned the
cabin, Henry was beside himself.
Didn't talk to me for two hours!
Can you believe that? I let him
be, of course. I really don't
know what to do for him.
My husband
was in an accident.
I'm so sorry.
You didn't know? I thought
since you two were friends
that she would've told you.
We're not friends.
We just met.
Oh, well! I didn't mean to
dampen casual conversation
with unexpected
depth. Excuse me.
Are you guys going
to be staying overnight?
In that small shack? No! We just
thought we'd whiz by, see and
how you were
doing, maybe stay for a cozy
little dinner? Who am I kidding?
Of course we'll stay for dinner!
It's been so long since
I've seen you guys, alone.
Well, I then better
stock up on some delectables.
Nice to meet you, Jack.
Very nice to
meet you, Mrs. O'Connell.
She's an author. Hence
the unusual vocabulary.
Ah, but of course.
Uh, I've gotta
go. I've got some things in here
that are going to thaw if I
don't get them to the fridge-
Yeah, please. By all means.
Hey, it was good seeing you.
I just realized I should
probably tell them I'm leaving.
Yeah.
Alice! I'm going to
see you guys back at the cabin.
Bye, Abby.
[IN BAD ACCENT]
I'm Scottish. Look at me.
Nyah nyah blah blah blah.
Abby...
I have a new
urban fantasy novel. It's
been in the top 100 sales
in Kindle for a week now.
That's great, Alice!
It's good. Not bad, not bad.
Who was that man we met today?
The landscaper?
Jack was his name.
Handsome!
I'm just glad
he wasn't British. Scottish I
can handle.
I'm not interested in
Jack. You don't have to worry.
Good.
Henry!
I'm just being honest.
Well, quit it.
There's only one man in
my life. You guys know that.
Abby, honey. You're gonna have
to let go of the rope someday.
What's your book about?
It's about a woman moving on.
No, it's not. And she can take
all the time
she needs. What's the rush?
Looks like I'll
be driving tonight.
We already agreed on that. With
my night vision, you need to-
You know I
was hoping that someone would be
able to help me with navigating.
Enough!
It's like you don't even feel it
that we're
here in our son's home.
You don't even show
you care that he's dead.
Where is that
coming from, Henry? Is that why
you're glugging that like
it's water? Because we're here?
Some people don't handle
grief the same way you do . They
don't mope around and act as if
they died, too. They try their
very best to rise up from the
ashes and live a good life. To
honor their son so that
if by God he is watching us,
he doesn't have to hurt
anymore. Do you think if Max
were here that he'd want
to see the pain you hold onto
like some badge of love?
Do you? Do you
think he wants to see his father
hurting like this because if he
does, he's not the boy I raised.
And don't you dare ever, ever
insinuate again
to me that my heart
didn't shatter when he died.
Because
every day I want to see him.
And I can't. And every day
I want to say goodbye to him
in a different way than the way
I did that night at the party.
I want to
say, Max, you are the best
person I have ever met.
And I
want to say I can't believe what
an amazing man my little boy
grew up to be
I want to hold him!
God!
I am so sorry.
What can I do? You can't
tell them. They'd never-
I hate to kick you
out of your own bed.
It's totally fine. I slept on
the couch when Lorna came
to visit.
It's really
comfortable, actually.
Lorna came? How is she?
She's well.
How are she and Barry
doing? Are they still happy?
You know about that?
Barry came to
see us a number of times
after that
night. He was a wreck.
I think he always
felt that Max
was the better man,
and maybe he was.
But Barry has a good
heart and he's very loyal.
He is that.
I've known
that boy since he was fourteen.
He confided in me that he loved
Lorna a long time ago.
And here we just thought
he loved messing with her.
Oh, he wanted to
mess with her, alright.
Alice!
Let's just hope that
he can maintain his sobriety.
Amen.
They're
behind the frame, Dad.
Dad. The photograph.
Dad! Get up. They're right here!
Dad, they're right fucking here!
You sure this is okay, kiddo?
Of course. I
don't mind the couch.
You've always
hated that couch.
I used to mind the couch,
but now it's growing on me.
Well, I really appreciate it.
I just want to sleep until my
eyes look normal
again. I can't go out like this.
I like the company.
It must get lonely here.
I'm not lonely. I'm fine.
HENRY:
Night, kiddo.
Guys?
Something wrong?
I just wanted
you to know, Max
knows how much you
love him. How much you miss him.
How do you know that, Abby?
I just have a
feeling. You know we're watched
over by the ones we love
the most after they've
moved on. I believe that.
Well, I hope
he isn't watching us.
What?
I hate to think there's
something great out there
waiting for him
and he's stuck here with us.
Mom.
HENRY:
Alice.
ALICE:
I mean it's true!
And to see my outburst tonight.
I can't think
of a worse torture.
I haven't seen any light, Mom.
If our boy is
still around, I'm sorry I
want him to stay here.
I don't have
anywhere else to go.
Well, that's
just selfish. I'm sorry.
I'm not doing anything!
Is it selfish
that I don't want to leave?
Max has been set free from
this. And there's more than
this. There is!
How do you know?
Well, I don't believe that.
I just know.
And you know it, too.
Goodnight Henry.
Goodnight, Dad.
Goodnight, Abby.
Well, that was awful.
I know you're here.
Max?
[SIGHS]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[SOFT CONTEMPLATIVE
PIANO AND ORCHESTRA]
[ORCHESTRA CONTINUES]
Abs.
Hey, handsome.
You done playing hide and seek?
I was working some things out.
Without me?
Without you.
That's not exactly fair, is it?
Neither is my staying here.
Neither is your leaving here.
Abs.
No! I heard
you tell you dad you have
nowhere else to go!
That doesn't mean I should
make you wait around for me.
I'm not waiting around.
I'm just here. I'm just-
Here.
There's nothing
wrong with that, Max.
Come on.
I don't care what
anybody else wants! I want you.
You seemed pretty happy
flirting with
that lumberjack guy.
I was just talking to him!
You had that light in your eyes.
I had no light in my eyes!
If anyone knows
that light, it's me.
I was just being nice.
You should be. You should be
nice to men who like
you and can hold
you and make love to you.
Oh God, you're killing me.
And can grab your hands when
you're
about to fall off a cliff.
I'm begging you Max.
Hug his
parents. Chop wood.
Stop!
You should have
a man who can be a man.
I'm not a man anymore.
I can never touch you again.
Kiss you again.
Feel your legs
wrapped around me again.
Please don't do this!
You know how that makes a
man feel, to not be
able to touch his own wife?
Stop saying these things
neither of us want to hear.
Please.
Why can't I
keep her? You gave me this
chance to be with her again. How
come I know it's wrong to stay?
Fuck! You are killing me
all over again. And that guy...
is that what you
want? What are you
trying to do? Torture me?
Stay away from us.
Leave us alone.
Where are you going?
To the bridge.
Where
I proposed to you?
Yep.
Abby, you're not wearing shoes.
I don't need them anymore.
You're doing this?
I'm going to make it
so I can touch you again.
You can't do
this, Abby. It feels really bad.
I don't know why I
know, but you shouldn't do this.
That's just the remnants
of your human existence talking.
No. It's more than that.
I have to.
[SCREAMS]
Abigail! Don't get in
that fucking car. I mean it!
Make me.
Help me! Help me!
Dear
God, help me. I know this isn't
right. What do I do?
[DRAMATIC
PIANO AND ORCHESTRA]
Guy's got taste. Hey!
You need to get off
your ass and go to the
bridge and you need to go now.
Listen you fuck, you need to get
your ass off the couch and go
save my wife!
You heard me. You can
hear me, can't you? Somewhere in
there, you
can hear what I'm saying to you.
Look, we're losing time here.
You have to get up, get your
keys and go to the bridge.
Jack, I'm
beggin' you. Go to the bridge.
Go to the fucking bridge.
Go to the fucking bridge, Jack!
Go! Go now!
That's
it, run. Run you bastard, run!
ABBY:
Max?
[DRAMATIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[CAR DRIVING SOUNDS]
ABBY:
Max?
Abby. Abby just
wait a few minutes!
Come on,
look at me. Please climb down.
God damnit,
Abigail, climb down now!
[EXHALES]
Come on, look at me.
Where are you?
Abby, I'm right here.
Can't you hear me? Look at
me. God damnit, let me talk to
her! What are you doing? What?
Is this her decision
to make or something?
Okay.
Oh God baby
just don't! Don't! Oh God,
don't jump. baby
I am begging you.
Let me talk to her!
Oh God. I don't want to die.
I don't want
to die. I don't want to die.
Abby! Abby!
[CRYING]
I got you. I got you.
[MUSIC FADES]
I'm going to sleep on the sofa.
But if you need anything,
at all, I will be right there,
okay? And I left you some water.
It's right over there, so.
[SOBS]
No, no, hey, hey, hey.
No, don't do
that. Don't do that. I don't
blame you for what
you were trying to do.
There was
a time I thought of stepping
out, too. I've been there. Hell,
I think we've all been there at
some point or another, depending
on how much
heartbreak we've had.
I lost my wife three
years ago to Leukemia.
Oh Jack. I'm so sorry.
Yeah, me too.
Me too.
It hurt, it hurt really
bad for a long time.
But you
have to believe me when I say
that I understand.
Because I do.
I do. But with a little bit of
time Abby, it won't hurt as bad.
You learn to see the beauty in
life again.
I'm rambling. I'm rambling.
Um...
Get some sleep.
MAX:
Abs?
[EMOTIONAL ORCHESTRA FADES IN]
You just had to
go and be a good guy.
I'm taking a gardening class.
Shut up.
No I actually really
like it. There's something very
meditative about getting my
fingers dirty with raw earth.
[ROOSTER CUCKOOS]
Did I hear dirty and raw?
Yeah you did.
LORNA:
Is that Jack?
Yeah it's him.
Hey, tell that guy
I'm still not sure about him.
I will not. Ignore Barry,
but you can
tell Jack that I said he's
turned you into a bumpkin. Next
thing I know
you'll be listening to country.
Oh we're
listening to it right now.
Shut the fuck up.
I'm kidding.
I'm listening to
classic rock all the way.
Listen I have to go.
We're going to go to the store
and get a book on mulch.
That sounds gross.
Bye.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
JACK:
Ready to go?
Mhm.
Let's hit it.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Max? Are you here?
I just thought I'd try
one last time. I'm so sorry
I couldn't jump, I just. If
you're listening. I love you.
Always.
Goodbye Abigail Lyons.
You made life worth living.
I did what you want.
So why
am I here? She can't see me
anymore. You blocked me out. So
why am I still here?
HENRY:
Max!
I'm here, Dad. I'm here.
I miss you.
I love you, Dad.
I love you so much.
I love you. Let go.
Hold on. Just one more.
I love you so much, Ma.
Thank you for being so strong.
[EMOTIONAL ORCHESTRA]
Abby?
I've been waiting for you.
But.
You were here, but then you went
there so you could come back
here, now. Don't think about it.
You'll remember soon.
It's a little fuzzy
for people when they first
come through.
Time isn't the same here.
What about?
Jack's with Emma now. We kept
each other company during our
living years.
Thank you for that.
So, you and me?
Soulmates, idiot. I hate to tell
you but, you're stuck with me.
[ORCHESTRA SWELLS]
[ORCHESTRA FADES]
[SOFT PIANO CONTINUES]
[SOFT ORCHESTRA CONTINUES]
[MUSIC FADES]